<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stanley Zheng</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Stanley Zheng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 10:01:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stanzheng.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Transit Camp NYC 2019!</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/transit-camp-nyc-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/transit-camp-nyc-2019/</guid><description>I went to Transit Camp NYC 2019 and had a wonderful time! I heard about the event from some mutual friends. I was really into civic tech which I think is a subset of transit planning. It is really exciting to hear about grass root organizing and transit organization meeting together to talk about big ideas.
The whole day was full of unconferences that made it a dynamic conference set by the people there in the room.</description></item><item><title>How well do you know your Cloud?</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/gcp-architecture/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/gcp-architecture/</guid><description>Back in May, I shared on Linkedin that I received my Google Cloud Architect certification. It was probably my most shared post ever on the platform. A week later, I attained the Data Engineer certification and at the beginning of July, the Associate Cloud Engineer. I ventured to guess that I was the first engineer at Cloudreach to get all three. I get a few common questions and I hoped to answer all here:</description></item><item><title>Cheap Haircuts in Manhattan for Now</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/cheap-haircuts-in-manhattan-for-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 05:05:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/cheap-haircuts-in-manhattan-for-now/</guid><description>On an island where dollar* pizza is no longer a dollar and brunch is repacked as breakfast with booze for $$$ it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to find value. But if you look hard and are a bit adventurous there are still some pockets left in Manhattan that we should all frequent.
An example of this is a small barber shop, near the flight walk down below the Shui Mei Cafe (67 E Broadway St).</description></item><item><title>Margin of Error: LaGuardia to Gate in 30 Mins</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/laguardia-to-gate-in-30-mins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:28:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/laguardia-to-gate-in-30-mins/</guid><description>1:23 PM I was sweating through my seat awaiting take off for the flight back home to Norfolk today. I attempted to calculate how narrow of a window I had to be there at that moment. While studying for my SA Pro, I learned some techniques for calculating risk and probability so I decided to quantify the odds.
10:00 AM I left for the airport via the F train to Laguardia in the morning around 10 am.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Web Services Certified!</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/aws-solutions-certified/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/aws-solutions-certified/</guid><description>I was able to get my solutions architect Exam this past week and wanted to share my experience. This was the solutions architect exam available before Feb 2018 and not the new one.
INTRO Amazon maintains 9 different certifications and specialties that you become certified in. Most of the certifications are valid for 2 years. Some are pre-requests for others; for example, the Solutions Architect Associate is required before taking the professional but some exams such as the Cloud Practioner have no requisites.</description></item><item><title>Serverless IAM Permissions</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/serverless-iam-permissions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/serverless-iam-permissions/</guid><description>How do we create an IAM (Identity Access Management) user with the bare minimum permissions to access the resources it needs for Serverless? What do the individual IAM services and permissions mean?
Intro In the wonderful world of Amazon lambda, you write the function code and execute it on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure. But outside of just Amazon Lambda there are multiple other Amazon resources your Lambda taps into including API Gateway, Cloudformation and more depending on what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description></item><item><title>AWS Lambda with Python</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/simple-aws-lambda-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:06:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/simple-aws-lambda-python/</guid><description>Update The bundle of this code is interesting but the bundle is huge! I recommend trying out either of the solutions below.
Serverless Framework AWS Serverless Application Model Intro AWS Lambda is a hosted platform for running code in the Amazon ecosystem. It supports multiple runtimes including Python! I found that although writing the logic code is easy, there are some unintuitive things that I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled over.</description></item><item><title>NPM Food - Emojis &#43; NPM Packaging</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2017/npm-food-unicode-emoji/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 12:06:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2017/npm-food-unicode-emoji/</guid><description>npm install -g food If we installed this package from NPM, what do we expect this to do? What kind of interface would we expect this to implement? I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure; This was one of those ideas that I had a spark of an idea and started four years ago. Watching the package go stale and be empty for years reminded me I should try and provide another valuable node package to the world.</description></item><item><title>RC 12: return statement;</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/return-statement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:01:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/return-statement/</guid><description>The Winter 1 2016 batch of the Recurse Center ended on Thursday, Feb 9th, 2017; on the following day, I had a long seven-hour bus ride home to reflect on the last three months. Did I accomplish what I set out to do? Did I become a better programmer? How would I describe my experience to others?
I&amp;rsquo;ll be direct and say my experience at Recurse was overly positive and I&amp;rsquo;m still in awe that it exists.</description></item><item><title>RC 11: Stanleybot 🤖 1.Oh.n0</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ai-chatbots/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 01:07:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ai-chatbots/</guid><description>During my last week at Recurse, I wanted to apply the knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ve gained about Machine Learning into a project. During my batch, I spent a portion of my time immersing myself with the terminology, concepts, and tooling but not as much as I hoped building and applying what I&amp;rsquo;d learned.
On the final week, I wanted to attempt one of the projects on my back burner for a while.</description></item><item><title>RC 10: Preparing for the Software Interview</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/interview-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 17:18:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/interview-prep/</guid><description>Software interviewing practices in the US usually involve a combination of the below
Phone Screens Team Pairing Take Home Projects Design and Architecture Interviews Whiteboard Interviews Hopefully, I am not alone in the shared dread of whiteboarding. As developers who type source code, use tools and reference documentation, approaching problems on the whiteboard is far removed from what we&amp;rsquo;re used to. I want to focus on some tips that have helped me prepare better for white boarding.</description></item><item><title>RC 9: QDraw - Exploring Google&#39;s Hidden Character API</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/qdraw-hidden-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 11:43:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/qdraw-hidden-api/</guid><description>QDraw was an RC project I worked on in December in the last week of my batch. I was inspired to build something similar to QuickDraw, a thinkwithgoogle.com project, which allowed you to play Pictionary against the machine. I had been studying machine learning during my batch and thought it was an excellent fun project to try and make. I thought about how I could translate the canvas positions to lines but couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a way to generate enough tag data to make it work.</description></item><item><title>RC 8: Alternative to GSuite: Named domains with Zoho</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ditching-gsuite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 11:43:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ditching-gsuite/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long supporter of Google Services; Practically it&amp;rsquo;s wired into our online identity. And the nature of your Google account, it touches everything now. It builds value when it can aggregate all the parts of your identity across their properties. Just check out your Google MyActivities, they have information on all your interaction with all of Google&amp;rsquo;s services across your devices. The difficulty of sticking with GSuite means splitting your data between different profiles.</description></item><item><title>RC 7: Chrome Productivity Extensions</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/7-code-productivity-chrome-exts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 19:54:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/7-code-productivity-chrome-exts/</guid><description>Extensions are an excellent way to augment a browser user experience to be more useful for the user. However, extensions can also make your browser less performant and even open security issues for your browser. When I install any Chrome Extension I look at their requested permissions and better yet source to make sure they are sensible. Most of these extensions are catered towards software developers and are very practical and familiar for approaching the web.</description></item><item><title>RC 6: Quantified Checkin</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/halfway-checkin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 15:55:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/halfway-checkin/</guid><description>My time at the Recurse Center is halfway over, and the next portion starts this Tuesday on Jan 3rd in the new year after a week hiatus. There will be ~30 new faces joining and only 6 weeks left of the batch left. Two months have flown by and so much has been done it&amp;rsquo;s hard to gather and describe so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to quantify it integers and data form.</description></item><item><title>RC 5: Code &amp;&amp; People</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/more-to-rc-than-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 15:00:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/more-to-rc-than-code/</guid><description>Software is more than code, its includes the people and communities that form around them. Code and humans are irrevocably inseparable (for now&amp;hellip;) and while at the Recurse Center we are focused on writing code, building projects, and exploring new concepts it&amp;rsquo;s hard to ignore the people and the human elements in the mix.
Often when I&amp;rsquo;m asked to describe the Recurse Center, I tend to talk more about the people and ideas being shared instead of the physical space or even projects we work on.</description></item><item><title>RC 4: Debugging debugging</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/debugging-debugging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:13:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/debugging-debugging/</guid><description>Debugging is easy, the answer is always the the last place you look. Mastery of debugging I would argue is a more valuable skill than programming itself. Often the worst feelings are staring at your code hopelessly trying to understand where the logic is breaking down.
At Recurse, there are lots of ways to tap into help. We have Zulip stream&amp;rsquo;s dedicated to every programming language imaginable, #pairing, #advice, and even just plain #help.</description></item><item><title>RC 3: Applying to the Recurse Center</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/the-application-process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 16:50:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/the-application-process/</guid><description>Notes from past Recursers on applying to recurse helped me navigate the process and keep my sanity. John Hergenroeder&amp;rsquo;s was especially insightful so I hope this can do the same and add another data point.
High-level timeline This is my timeline, I wanted to join Winter 1 which started in November so I made sure to follow up as fast as possible.
Timeline October 7 - Started Application October 9 - Applied October 14 - Initial Callback October 15 - First Round interview October 17 - Notification for Second Round October 19 - Second Round interview October 23 - Admission Notice October 25 - Invited to RC Community Forum &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Github Wiki November 7 - Day 1 February 7 - Last day Submit an Application For the initial application, it asks you a few questions and asks you to submit a succinct code gist that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use frameworks or require too much background knowledge to be understood by a reader.</description></item><item><title>Chromecast&#43;TTS = Party: PA.js</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/chromecast-party-broadcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 09:37:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/chromecast-party-broadcast/</guid><description>I put this together in an afternoon hack session and was planning to extend it and clean up the code. However, its been months and the holidays are rolling around and it&amp;rsquo;s yet to be published! I wanted to put out a small writeup how to harness your Chromecasts for home automation, scripting, and fun.
Back at my previous job, we had installed Chromecasts throughout the building hooked up to speakers and TVs.</description></item><item><title>RC 2: Organizing Your Ideas</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/week-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 14:48:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/week-1/</guid><description>Note: The title was renamed to RC:2 from Week1 to better reflect these entries as a series but not by week
Settling In Each week I hope to go deeper and highlight something I&amp;rsquo;m working on at Recurse. Coming into Recurse I aimed to get into a routine and continue it throughout the twelve weeks. I read the community wikipedia and all the accounts I could find online about how I could make the most out of my time at the center.</description></item><item><title>RC 1: Orientation</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 14:45:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/day-1/</guid><description>Note: The title was renamed to RC:1 from Day1 to better reflect these entries as a series but not by week
Day one of RC is widely different from every other day. Its more structured and is full of presentations and socializing. This is my personal account from my day one experience, your experience may vary. They are always changing and aiming to improve the first day experience.
Getting to NYC I took the bus up from Norfolk, Virginia to New York Saturday night.</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2016</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/all-things-open/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 17:57:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/all-things-open/</guid><description>Raleigh All Things Open is an amazing conference in its fourth year running hosted in Raleigh North Carolina. It&amp;rsquo;s a conference that celebrates open source and the community behind it. Two days of pure learning, networking and fun times with fellow developers.
Early-Registration. Over 2000+ Attendees for two days.
You Should Go Affordable: for $199 this was a very inexpensive conference. The conference hotel for one day cost more than two days of tickets including great after hours celebrations on three days.</description></item><item><title>Joining Recurse Center</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/recurse/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 16:31:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/recurse/hello-world/</guid><description>New York City for the Winter I am excited to call the Recurse Center in NYC home for the next few months. Will be a part of their 12 weeks for Winter 2016 batch. Recurse describes itself as a free, self-directed, educational retreat for people who want to get better at programming, whether they&amp;rsquo;ve been coding for three decades or three months. There are facilitators but for 12 weeks you will be working with your fellow batchmates on honing your skills working on projects you always wanted to do.</description></item><item><title>Blog Necromancer</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/blog-necromancer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 02:55:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/blog-necromancer/</guid><description>Pardon the Cobwebs It&amp;rsquo;s only fitting that we raise the dead on Halloween. When I first started out developing, I was encouraged to write down more of my day to day insight so I could share and reflect. I started with Jekyll originally for my blog. I was really proud of it but after a while and my lack of using Ruby on any of my system I gave it up.</description></item><item><title>Easy Server Sync</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/easy-server-sync/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 01:23:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/easy-server-sync/</guid><description>You can setup some great tools like browsersync or built in editor features to keep your comptuer synced with a remote server. This can add some benefits such as being able to have a staging/live server and demo in real time to a sharable remote. However setting up all those tools isn&amp;rsquo;t always fun for small tasks.
In OSX/Linux there are some basic unix tools that you can use in combination to simulate the same effects.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Code: Up and Running</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/vscode-the-good-parts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 17:28:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/vscode-the-good-parts/</guid><description>Try it! You might just like it! Visual Studio Code is Microsoft’s cross-platform text editor that was announced in April of 2015 and open sourced on Github in November. It has a similar look and feel to Sublime and Atom and is a quick responsive basic editor with polished tooling. When I started web development, I started using Sublime Text 2&amp;frasl;3 in 2012; but as time passed, it seemed sublime was stagnating with the product with fewer releases and interesting features.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw 3 - Mocha</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:24:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-3/</guid><description>Here is my solution to Sharpen Your Saw 3. We had Steve Hackbarth down again to teach about a core skill in development: testing. We used the popular test runner Mocha.
The project went through different setups proving although complex, a stateless purely functional component is easy to test. Repo.
Each pull request represents a solution.
Here is my solution.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw 2 - Async</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-2/</guid><description>About Hacking Async with Steve Hackbarth, here are a few solutions provided by our fellow meetup users Steve Hackbarth is back again this February to lead an interactive meet-up to discuss problem-solving using Javascript and other useful utilities. Be sure to bring your laptop so you can participate in the exercises.
Slides: http://ursahealth.github.io/async.html
The challenge was to find all word with the most synonyms in the phrase. &amp;ldquo;May the force be with you&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw - Lodash</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw/</guid><description>Intro &amp;ldquo;Steve Hackbarth presented Sharpen your Saw, discussing problem-solving using JavaScript and other useful&amp;rdquo; utilities. Participants were encouraged to bring laptops to participate in code exercises.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the topics covered by the Monday Norfolk.js meetup:
Steve Hackbarth presented Sharpen your Saw, discussing problem-solving using Javascript and other useful utilities. Participants were encouraged to bring laptops to participate in code exercises.
Participants could use jsfiddle.net Some of the utilities used were underscore.</description></item><item><title>Prepping for a Technical Interview</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/prepping-for-a-technical-interview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 18:43:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/prepping-for-a-technical-interview/</guid><description>Intro I gave a talk at my local ACM about how to prepare for technical interviews. It&amp;rsquo;s a topic not emphasized on much at my school and I wanted to give students some advice about starting and what helped me.
Algorithms Learn about Big O notation and try being able to recognize their O(time). Perform two sortings. O(nLog(n)) QuickSort &amp;amp; Merge Sort maybe familiar yourself with others Tree Traversals in, post, pre order, breadth/level depth tree structures, binary, trinary, heap trees, AVL Graph problems&amp;hellip; Dijkstra, A, common n = np problems.</description></item><item><title>CodeforAmerica in the Local News</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/news-mentions-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/news-mentions-/</guid><description> I Volunteer a bunch for CodeforAmerica so we end up being mentioned once in a while.
Virginia Pilot http://hamptonroads.com/2013/05/hackers-put-white-hats-civic-duty-norfolk http://hamptonroads.com/2013/04/summer-internships-outlook-improving-slowly ODU News http://www.odu.edu/news/2013/5/code_for_america
AltDaily http://www.altdaily.com/features/news/6274-a-roundup-of-saturday-s-hack-for-change http://www.altdaily.com/features/news/119-politics34/5273-32tracking-hrt-buses-in-real-time-let-s-make-a-transit-api http://www.altdaily.com/features/news/7001-old-couch-theres-an-app-for-that-norfolk-launches-citizen-request-app http://www.altdaily.com/features/entertainment/137-lifestyle52/7006-follow-cutiesinnorfolk-because-these-kittens-tho Pebble Developer Blog https://developer.getpebble.com/blog/2014/03/20/pebble-goes-to-pennapps/</description></item><item><title>Prepping for a Google Interview</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/notes/algorithims/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 21:43:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/notes/algorithims/</guid><description>These are a bunch of notes I took when I was reading through Cracking the Coding Interview in prep for a Google Interview
spelling algorithms correctly is important peaks
insertion sort always O(N^2) because going through and moving binary sort can assist it to be O(log(n)n) for insertions but still N^2 for swaps merge sort two arrays, sort, then merge, then split and repeat. O(log(n)n) complexity priority queue - maxheap, nodes are always larger than or equal to their children (max heap property) minheap, nodes are always smaller than or equal to their children (min heap property) heap sort &amp;ndash; heap on a tree, (breadth first view,) int array[7]; indexies -AVL trees traverse = n insert nlog(n) delete min find next min and max and next smaller and next min log(n), Comparison Model -Searching: (lng) -Sorting nln(n) -All input items are blackboxes In reality</description></item><item><title>C&#43;&#43; Standards in Education</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/c&#43;&#43;-standard-and-education/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/c&#43;&#43;-standard-and-education/</guid><description>I learned mostly C++99 standards throughout my time at my CS Course program. Actually scratch that, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even explained the different in standards. Even from traditional C, or C99, its funny how institutions focus on learning but give only a breadth first generalistic approach to most education.
Another argument is if C++ is the best language to be taught in intro programming courses compared to Java or even C# (or the ideal Python).</description></item><item><title>Gestice: PennApps Spring 2014</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/gestice-pennapps-spring-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 14:14:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/gestice-pennapps-spring-2014/</guid><description>PennApps 2014 We create a secure way to unlock your phone and launch apps. A companion app for pebble for the android platform, shake to unlock. Not only will your phone have an extra layer of security, Gestice allows you to train any Android App on your phone to a gesture.
These crazy kids today. Use your Pebble and accelerometer to bring your Android to life. Shake, shake. Shake, shake.</description></item><item><title>Font Awesome Recipes</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/font-awesome-recipes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 23:51:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/font-awesome-recipes/</guid><description>Quick Recipes for Making Composed Font awesome icons Some recipes I put together to make composed font awesome icons.
Checkmark
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;fa-stack fa-lg&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i style=&amp;quot;color:green&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;fa fa-circle fa-stack-2x&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-check fa-stack-1x fa-inverse&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; Error
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;fa-stack fa-lg&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i style=&amp;quot;color:#ff0202&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;fa fa-circle fa-stack-2x&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-times fa-stack-1x fa-inverse&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; Questionable
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;fa-stack fa-lg&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i style=&amp;quot;color:gray&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;fa fa-circle fa-stack-2x&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-question fa-stack-1x fa-inverse&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; Site Navigation buttons</description></item><item><title>DE Hackathon with Appcelerator</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/dominion-enterprises-hack-university-hackathon-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 23:53:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/dominion-enterprises-hack-university-hackathon-2/</guid><description>Dominion Enterprises Hackathon A hackathon, also known as a hack day, hack fest or code fest, is an event in which computer programmers and others involved in software development, including graphic designers, interface designers, and project managers, collaborate intensively on software projects.
This was Dominion&amp;rsquo;s Seventh hackathon and the second edition of HackU, a hackathon where schools were invited across Virginia. Paired with three coaches and given 24 hours, each team was read a challenge on gamification and set off to build something.</description></item><item><title>Quick Serve it!</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/simple-http-servers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 11:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/simple-http-servers/</guid><description>Sometimes you need to serve a directory to a group in a small room.
Using Node
npm install http-server -g http-server # another port # http-server -p 9080 Want to run it forever in production? Run it forever
forever start ../node_modules/http-server/bin/http-server # path the last argument to http-server and path it to where you want Using Python
python -m SimpleHTTPServer # specify port number via python -m SimpleHTTPServer 8080 Using Php</description></item><item><title>Develop Java in Sublime</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/run-java-in-sublime/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 22:09:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/run-java-in-sublime/</guid><description>This is for mac on sublime.
It makes it a bit easier to build and run java everytime you compile. Speeds up from moving to terminal each time.
using sublime or text editor is sometimes unmanagable for java but the anti-eclipse club is strong&amp;hellip;
//Build and run java, works on OSX 10.9 Mavericks and Sublime and up { &amp;quot;cmd&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;javac \&amp;quot;$file_name\&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; java \&amp;quot;$file_base_name\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;shell&amp;quot;: true, &amp;quot;file_regex&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;^(...*?):([0-9]*):?([0-9]*)&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;selector&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;source.java&amp;quot; }</description></item><item><title>Google Glass at MHacks</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/mhacks-spring14-/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 23:27:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/mhacks-spring14-/</guid><description>These are some notes over the night of January 17-19th for Mhacks_III in its Raw blog form. My friend Jose and I both brought our Google Glass and we were determined to build a cool Google glass Hack at MHacks this year in Detroit.
The hack: Codename Archimedies using the glass as a medical device for assisted living. Tech used. + Mirror API + Bootstrap + PHP/Yii + MySQL</description></item><item><title>Developing for Google Glass</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/developing-for-glass/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 15:25:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/developing-for-glass/</guid><description>Some caveats to a good glass app Inspired by the good principals of a good web app.
follows similar style and UX principals in other apps natural usage in day to day life. GDK on the client, voice recognition and translate avaliable on the client. Standard Android API and Paradigms
Types - invocation - elements GDK OK GLASS MIRROR MENU ITEM GDK + Mirror Timeline card Gesture Detector - touch pad movement Voice Trigger - specify use Card Scroller &amp;amp; Cards(builder)- build timeline cards and arrange to scroll through them Live Card - real time info</description></item><item><title>Glass Memory Assistant</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/glass-memory-assistant/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:37:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/glass-memory-assistant/</guid><description>I worked on a Glass memory assistant at a past Hackathon. It ended up not working out well but many companies are going into space. This was put together for an exercise that required responding to how a technology today can fill a gap in technology in the past in a more efficient way.
From a study in 2001 in leveraging personal mobile tech and using natural language recognition operation</description></item><item><title>Tricks when Developing on Android with Java</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/android-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 16:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/android-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Components of android Activities -email client Services -music player Content Providers - Note taking app or contacts Broadcast Receiver -The intent deliverer Logcat filtering without eclipse.
adb logcat | grep --line-buffered &amp;quot;mysearch&amp;quot; to pipe out to txt file
adb logcat | grep --line-buffered &amp;quot;mysearch&amp;quot; &amp;gt; mylog.txt open and visit website via intent
adb bash am start -a android.intent.action.VIEW -d http://www.stackoverflow.com Build from commandline an android project (replace &amp;lsquo;Hello with name of Project&amp;rsquo;)</description></item><item><title>Google Glass: First Impressions</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/living-with-glass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 16:08:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/living-with-glass/</guid><description>Wearing glass in the wild is a very social experience. Often it draws a few stares and people are curious, is it on or is it off? What does it do.
This blog reflecting on a developer who returned glass after 30 days http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/01/05/i-return-ed-my-google-glass-after-30-days/ struck
Impressions Voice - the gdk offered voice recognition is amazing good, and its suprising that this is performed on the client side. Also new apps sideloaded also can have their apps specified by the voicd command trigger predefined.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/dockercon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/dockercon/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>