<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018s on Stanley Zheng</title><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018s on Stanley Zheng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 10:01:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How well do you know your Cloud?</title><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/gcp-architecture/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/gcp-architecture/</guid><description>Back in May, I shared on Linkedin that I received my Google Cloud Architect certification. It was probably my most shared post ever on the platform. A week later, I attained the Data Engineer certification and at the beginning of July, the Associate Cloud Engineer. I ventured to guess that I was the first engineer at Cloudreach to get all three. I get a few common questions and I hoped to answer all here:</description></item><item><title>Cheap Haircuts in Manhattan for Now</title><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/cheap-haircuts-in-manhattan-for-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 05:05:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/cheap-haircuts-in-manhattan-for-now/</guid><description>On an island where dollar* pizza is no longer a dollar and brunch is repacked as breakfast with booze for $$$ it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to find value. But if you look hard and are a bit adventurous there are still some pockets left in Manhattan that we should all frequent.
An example of this is a small barber shop, near the flight walk down below the Shui Mei Cafe (67 E Broadway St).</description></item><item><title>Margin of Error: LaGuardia to Gate in 30 Mins</title><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/laguardia-to-gate-in-30-mins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:28:23 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/laguardia-to-gate-in-30-mins/</guid><description>1:23 PM I was sweating through my seat awaiting take off for the flight back home to Norfolk today. I attempted to calculate how narrow of a window I had to be there at that moment. While studying for my SA Pro, I learned some techniques for calculating risk and probability so I decided to quantify the odds.
10:00 AM I left for the airport via the F train to Laguardia in the morning around 10 am.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Web Services Certified!</title><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/aws-solutions-certified/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/aws-solutions-certified/</guid><description>I was able to get my solutions architect Exam this past week and wanted to share my experience. This was the solutions architect exam available before Feb 2018 and not the new one.
INTRO Amazon maintains 9 different certifications and specialties that you become certified in. Most of the certifications are valid for 2 years. Some are pre-requests for others; for example, the Solutions Architect Associate is required before taking the professional but some exams such as the Cloud Practioner have no requisites.</description></item><item><title>Serverless IAM Permissions</title><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/serverless-iam-permissions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/serverless-iam-permissions/</guid><description>How do we create an IAM (Identity Access Management) user with the bare minimum permissions to access the resources it needs for Serverless? What do the individual IAM services and permissions mean?
Intro In the wonderful world of Amazon lambda, you write the function code and execute it on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure. But outside of just Amazon Lambda there are multiple other Amazon resources your Lambda taps into including API Gateway, Cloudformation and more depending on what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description></item><item><title>AWS Lambda with Python</title><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/simple-aws-lambda-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:06:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/simple-aws-lambda-python/</guid><description>Update The bundle of this code is interesting but the bundle is huge! I recommend trying out either of the solutions below.
Serverless Framework AWS Serverless Application Model Intro AWS Lambda is a hosted platform for running code in the Amazon ecosystem. It supports multiple runtimes including Python! I found that although writing the logic code is easy, there are some unintuitive things that I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled over.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/dockercon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.zheng.nyc/2018/dockercon/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>