<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recurse on Stanley Zheng</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/tags/recurse/</link><description>Recent content in recurse on Stanley Zheng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stanzheng.com/blog/tags/recurse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interactive Engaging Ways to Learn SQL !</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/interactive-fun-ways-to-learn-sql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/interactive-fun-ways-to-learn-sql/</guid><description>There are so many sources to learn SQL on the internet
Here are some that I think teach in a cool and different way of learning SQL interactively or differently.
I hope to add more while I learn!
Interactively learn SQL through a story - https://www.executeprogram.com/ Quick reference cheat sheet - https://learnxinyminutes.com/docs/sql/ Solve a murder mystery and learn SQL while doing it! http://mystery.knightlab.com/ Learning Postgres through exercises, multiple tables beginner to expert.</description></item><item><title>RC 12: return statement;</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/return-statement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 14:01:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/return-statement/</guid><description>The Winter 1 2016 batch of the Recurse Center ended on Thursday, Feb 9th, 2017; on the following day, I had a long seven-hour bus ride home to reflect on the last three months. Did I accomplish what I set out to do? Did I become a better programmer? How would I describe my experience to others?
I&amp;rsquo;ll be direct and say my experience at Recurse was overly positive and I&amp;rsquo;m still in awe that it exists.</description></item><item><title>RC 11: Stanleybot 🤖 1.Oh.n0</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ai-chatbots/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 01:07:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ai-chatbots/</guid><description>During my last week at Recurse, I wanted to apply the knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ve gained about Machine Learning into a project. During my batch, I spent a portion of my time immersing myself with the terminology, concepts, and tooling but not as much as I hoped building and applying what I&amp;rsquo;d learned.
On the final week, I wanted to attempt one of the projects on my back burner for a while.</description></item><item><title>RC 9: QDraw - Exploring Google&#39;s Hidden Character API</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/qdraw-hidden-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 11:43:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/qdraw-hidden-api/</guid><description>QDraw was an RC project I worked on in December in the last week of my batch. I was inspired to build something similar to QuickDraw, a thinkwithgoogle.com project, which allowed you to play Pictionary against the machine. I had been studying machine learning during my batch and thought it was an excellent fun project to try and make. I thought about how I could translate the canvas positions to lines but couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a way to generate enough tag data to make it work.</description></item><item><title>RC 8: Alternative to GSuite: Named domains with Zoho</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ditching-gsuite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 11:43:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/ditching-gsuite/</guid><description>Edit This method isn&amp;rsquo;t possible anymore as email forwarding requires premium to forward email but sending email possible.
To use send from GMAIL from Zoho configure the below settings
Under Gmail -&amp;gt; Settings, Click &amp;ldquo;add a mail account&amp;rdquo; Select the email provider with smtp.zoho.com over port 465 using your confirmed email. This will use SSL over email. If you use SSO using another provider, you will have to generate a one time password to use from https://accounts.</description></item><item><title>RC 5: Code &amp;&amp; People</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/more-to-rc-than-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 15:00:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/more-to-rc-than-code/</guid><description>Software is more than code, its includes the people and communities that form around them. Code and humans are irrevocably inseparable (for now&amp;hellip;) and while at the Recurse Center we are focused on writing code, building projects, and exploring new concepts it&amp;rsquo;s hard to ignore the people and the human elements in the mix.
Often when I&amp;rsquo;m asked to describe the Recurse Center, I tend to talk more about the people and ideas being shared instead of the physical space or even projects we work on.</description></item><item><title>RC 4: Debugging debugging</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/debugging-debugging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:13:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/debugging-debugging/</guid><description>Debugging is easy, the answer is always the the last place you look. Mastery of debugging I would argue is a more valuable skill than programming itself. Often the worst feelings are staring at your code hopelessly trying to understand where the logic is breaking down.
At Recurse, there are lots of ways to tap into help. We have Zulip stream&amp;rsquo;s dedicated to every programming language imaginable, #pairing, #advice, and even just plain #help.</description></item><item><title>RC 3: Applying to the Recurse Center</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/the-application-process/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 16:50:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/the-application-process/</guid><description>Notes from past Recursers on applying to recurse helped me navigate the process and keep my sanity. John Hergenroeder&amp;rsquo;s was especially insightful so I hope this can do the same and add another data point.
High-level timeline This is my timeline, I wanted to join Winter 1 which started in November so I made sure to follow up as fast as possible.
Timeline October 7 - Started Application October 9 - Applied October 14 - Initial Callback October 15 - First Round interview October 17 - Notification for Second Round October 19 - Second Round interview October 23 - Admission Notice October 25 - Invited to RC Community Forum &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Github Wiki November 7 - Day 1 February 7 - Last day Submit an Application For the initial application, it asks you a few questions and asks you to submit a succinct code gist that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use frameworks or require too much background knowledge to be understood by a reader.</description></item><item><title>RC 2: Organizing Your Ideas</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/week-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 14:48:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/week-1/</guid><description>Note: The title was renamed to RC:2 from Week1 to better reflect these entries as a series but not by week
Settling In Each week I hope to go deeper and highlight something I&amp;rsquo;m working on at Recurse. Coming into Recurse I aimed to get into a routine and continue it throughout the twelve weeks. I read the community wikipedia and all the accounts I could find online about how I could make the most out of my time at the center.</description></item><item><title>RC 1: Orientation</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 14:45:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/recurse/day-1/</guid><description>Note: The title was renamed to RC:1 from Day1 to better reflect these entries as a series but not by week
Day one of RC is widely different from every other day. Its more structured and is full of presentations and socializing. This is my personal account from my day one experience, your experience may vary. They are always changing and aiming to improve the first day experience.
Getting to NYC I took the bus up from Norfolk, Virginia to New York Saturday night.</description></item><item><title>Joining Recurse Center</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/recurse/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 16:31:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/recurse/hello-world/</guid><description>New York City for the Winter I am excited to call the Recurse Center in NYC home for the next few months. Will be a part of their 12 weeks for Winter 2016 batch. Recurse describes itself as a free, self-directed, educational retreat for people who want to get better at programming, whether they&amp;rsquo;ve been coding for three decades or three months. There are facilitators but for 12 weeks you will be working with your fellow batchmates on honing your skills working on projects you always wanted to do.</description></item></channel></rss>