<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019s on Stanley Zheng</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/</link><description>Recent content in 2019s on Stanley Zheng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interactive Engaging Ways to Learn SQL !</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/interactive-fun-ways-to-learn-sql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/interactive-fun-ways-to-learn-sql/</guid><description>There are so many sources to learn SQL on the internet
Here are some that I think teach in a cool and different way of learning SQL interactively or differently.
I hope to add more while I learn!
Interactively learn SQL through a story - https://www.executeprogram.com/ Quick reference cheat sheet - https://learnxinyminutes.com/docs/sql/ Solve a murder mystery and learn SQL while doing it! http://mystery.knightlab.com/ Learning Postgres through exercises, multiple tables beginner to expert.</description></item><item><title>Standardizing your units</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/standardizing-your-units/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/standardizing-your-units/</guid><description>Nice Title A misconception I held that the US was on Imperial units. The US uses United States Customary Units (USCS), which has a common ancestry with English units but is different than imperial.
Some fun facts:
The only three countries in the world that don&amp;rsquo;t use metric are the USA, Liberia, and Myanmar. NASA lost a $125 million Mars orbiter because a Lockheed Martin engineering team used English units of measurement while the agency&amp;rsquo;s team used the more conventional metric system.</description></item><item><title>How Long Can You Go Without Eating?</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/how-long-can-you-go-without-eating/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 17:25:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/how-long-can-you-go-without-eating/</guid><description>Lately I have had more control over my schedule. I wanted to experiment with alternative diets and wanted to test going on a week long fast. I was able to make it about 6 days* without meals before I caved in.
There are some studies that show that fasting improves mental focus and energy. I had previously participated in the 16&amp;frasl;8 fast, where a participant eats in 8 hour windows and fasts for the rest.</description></item><item><title>Transit Camp NYC 2019!</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/transit-camp-nyc-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2019/transit-camp-nyc-2019/</guid><description>I went to Transit Camp NYC 2019 and had a wonderful time! I heard about the event from some mutual friends. I was really into civic tech which I think is a subset of transit planning. It is really exciting to hear about grass root organizing and transit organization meeting together to talk about big ideas.
The whole day was full of unconferences that made it a dynamic conference set by the people there in the room.</description></item></channel></rss>