<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Stanley Zheng</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Stanley Zheng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 14:37:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chromecast&#43;TTS = Party: PA.js</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/chromecast-party-broadcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 14:37:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/chromecast-party-broadcast/</guid><description>I put this together in an afternoon hack session and was planning to extend it and clean up the code. However, its been months and the holidays are rolling around and it&amp;rsquo;s yet to be published! I wanted to put out a small writeup how to harness your Chromecasts for home automation, scripting, and fun.
Back at my previous job, we had installed Chromecasts throughout the building hooked up to speakers and TVs.</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2016</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/all-things-open/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 17:57:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/all-things-open/</guid><description>Raleigh All Things Open is an amazing conference in its fourth year running hosted in Raleigh North Carolina. It&amp;rsquo;s a conference that celebrates open source and the community behind it. Two days of pure learning, networking and fun times with fellow developers.
Early-Registration. Over 2000+ Attendees for two days.
You Should Go Affordable: for $199 this was a very inexpensive conference. The conference hotel for one day cost more than two days of tickets including great after hours celebrations on three days.</description></item><item><title>Joining Recurse Center</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/recurse/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 16:31:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/recurse/hello-world/</guid><description>New York City for the Winter I am excited to call the Recurse Center in NYC home for the next few months. Will be a part of their 12 weeks for Winter 2016 batch. Recurse describes itself as a free, self-directed, educational retreat for people who want to get better at programming, whether they&amp;rsquo;ve been coding for three decades or three months. There are facilitators but for 12 weeks you will be working with your fellow batchmates on honing your skills working on projects you always wanted to do.</description></item><item><title>Blog Necromancer</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/blog-necromancer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 02:55:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/blog-necromancer/</guid><description>Pardon the Cobwebs It&amp;rsquo;s only fitting that we raise the dead on Halloween. When I first started out developing, I was encouraged to write down more of my day to day insight so I could share and reflect. I started with Jekyll originally for my blog. I was really proud of it but after a while and my lack of using Ruby on any of my system I gave it up.</description></item><item><title>Easy Server Sync</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/easy-server-sync/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 01:23:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/easy-server-sync/</guid><description>You can setup some great tools like browsersync or built in editor features to keep your comptuer synced with a remote server. This can add some benefits such as being able to have a staging/live server and demo in real time to a sharable remote. However setting up all those tools isn&amp;rsquo;t always fun for small tasks.
In OSX/Linux there are some basic unix tools that you can use in combination to simulate the same effects.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Code: Up and Running</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/vscode-the-good-parts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 17:28:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/vscode-the-good-parts/</guid><description>Try it! You might just like it! Visual Studio Code is Microsoft’s cross-platform text editor that was announced in April of 2015 and open sourced on Github in November. It has a similar look and feel to Sublime and Atom and is a quick responsive basic editor with polished tooling. When I started web development, I started using Sublime Text 2&amp;frasl;3 in 2012; but as time passed, it seemed sublime was stagnating with the product with fewer releases and interesting features.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw 3 - Mocha</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:24:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-3/</guid><description>Here is my solution to Sharpen Your Saw 3. We had Steve Hackbarth down again to teach about a core skill in development: testing. We used the popular test runner Mocha.
The project went through different setups proving although complex, a stateless purely functional component is easy to test. Repo.
Each pull request represents a solution.
Here is my solution.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw 2 - Async</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-2/</guid><description>About Hacking Async with Steve Hackbarth, here are a few solutions provided by our fellow meetup users Steve Hackbarth is back again this February to lead an interactive meet-up to discuss problem-solving using Javascript and other useful utilities. Be sure to bring your laptop so you can participate in the exercises.
Slides: http://ursahealth.github.io/async.html
The challenge was to find all word with the most synonyms in the phrase. &amp;ldquo;May the force be with you&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw - Lodash</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw/</guid><description>Intro &amp;ldquo;Steve Hackbarth presented Sharpen your Saw, discussing problem-solving using JavaScript and other useful&amp;rdquo; utilities. Participants were encouraged to bring laptops to participate in code exercises.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the topics covered by the Monday Norfolk.js meetup:
Steve Hackbarth presented Sharpen your Saw, discussing problem-solving using Javascript and other useful utilities. Participants were encouraged to bring laptops to participate in code exercises.
Participants could use jsfiddle.net Some of the utilities used were underscore.</description></item><item><title>Prepping for a Technical Interview</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/prepping-for-a-technical-interview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 18:43:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/prepping-for-a-technical-interview/</guid><description>Intro I gave a talk at my local ACM about how to prepare for technical interviews. It&amp;rsquo;s a topic not emphasized on much at my school and I wanted to give students some advice about starting and what helped me.
Algorithms Learn about Big O notation and try being able to recognize their O(time). Perform two sortings. O(nLog(n)) QuickSort &amp;amp; Merge Sort maybe familiar yourself with others Tree Traversals in, post, pre order, breadth/level depth tree structures, binary, trinary, heap trees, AVL Graph problems&amp;hellip; Dijkstra, A, common n = np problems.</description></item><item><title>CodeforAmerica in the Local News</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/news-mentions-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/news-mentions-/</guid><description> I Volunteer a bunch for CodeforAmerica so we end up being mentioned once in a while.
Virginia Pilot http://hamptonroads.com/2013/05/hackers-put-white-hats-civic-duty-norfolk http://hamptonroads.com/2013/04/summer-internships-outlook-improving-slowly ODU News http://www.odu.edu/news/2013/5/code_for_america
AltDaily http://www.altdaily.com/features/news/6274-a-roundup-of-saturday-s-hack-for-change http://www.altdaily.com/features/news/119-politics34/5273-32tracking-hrt-buses-in-real-time-let-s-make-a-transit-api http://www.altdaily.com/features/news/7001-old-couch-theres-an-app-for-that-norfolk-launches-citizen-request-app http://www.altdaily.com/features/entertainment/137-lifestyle52/7006-follow-cutiesinnorfolk-because-these-kittens-tho Pebble Developer Blog https://developer.getpebble.com/blog/2014/03/20/pebble-goes-to-pennapps/</description></item><item><title>Prepping for a Google Interview</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/notes/algorithims/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 21:43:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/notes/algorithims/</guid><description>These are a bunch of notes I took when I was reading through Cracking the Coding Interview in prep for a Google Interview
spelling algorithms correctly is important peaks
insertion sort always O(N^2) because going through and moving binary sort can assist it to be O(log(n)n) for insertions but still N^2 for swaps merge sort two arrays, sort, then merge, then split and repeat. O(log(n)n) complexity priority queue - maxheap, nodes are always larger than or equal to their children (max heap property) minheap, nodes are always smaller than or equal to their children (min heap property) heap sort &amp;ndash; heap on a tree, (breadth first view,) int array[7]; indexies -AVL trees traverse = n insert nlog(n) delete min find next min and max and next smaller and next min log(n), Comparison Model -Searching: (lng) -Sorting nln(n) -All input items are blackboxes In reality</description></item><item><title>C&#43;&#43; Standards in Education</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/c&#43;&#43;-standard-and-education/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/c&#43;&#43;-standard-and-education/</guid><description>I learned mostly C++99 standards throughout my time at my CS Course program. Actually scratch that, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t even explained the different in standards. Even from traditional C, or C99, its funny how institutions focus on learning but give only a breadth first generalistic approach to most education.
Another argument is if C++ is the best language to be taught in intro programming courses compared to Java or even C# (or the ideal Python).</description></item><item><title>Gestice: PennApps Spring 2014</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/gestice-pennapps-spring-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 14:14:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/gestice-pennapps-spring-2014/</guid><description>PennApps 2014 We create a secure way to unlock your phone and launch apps. A companion app for pebble for the android platform, shake to unlock. Not only will your phone have an extra layer of security, Gestice allows you to train any Android App on your phone to a gesture.
These crazy kids today. Use your Pebble and accelerometer to bring your Android to life. Shake, shake. Shake, shake.</description></item><item><title>Font Awesome Recipes</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/font-awesome-recipes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 23:51:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/font-awesome-recipes/</guid><description>Quick Recipes for Making Composed Font awesome icons Some recipes I put together to make composed font awesome icons.
Checkmark
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;fa-stack fa-lg&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i style=&amp;quot;color:green&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;fa fa-circle fa-stack-2x&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-check fa-stack-1x fa-inverse&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; Error
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;fa-stack fa-lg&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i style=&amp;quot;color:#ff0202&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;fa fa-circle fa-stack-2x&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-times fa-stack-1x fa-inverse&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; Questionable
&amp;lt;span class=&amp;quot;fa-stack fa-lg&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i style=&amp;quot;color:gray&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;fa fa-circle fa-stack-2x&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;fa fa-question fa-stack-1x fa-inverse&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; Site Navigation buttons</description></item><item><title>DE Hackathon with Appcelerator</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/dominion-enterprises-hack-university-hackathon-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 23:53:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/dominion-enterprises-hack-university-hackathon-2/</guid><description>Dominion Enterprises Hackathon A hackathon, also known as a hack day, hack fest or code fest, is an event in which computer programmers and others involved in software development, including graphic designers, interface designers, and project managers, collaborate intensively on software projects.
This was Dominion&amp;rsquo;s Seventh hackathon and the second edition of HackU, a hackathon where schools were invited across Virginia. Paired with three coaches and given 24 hours, each team was read a challenge on gamification and set off to build something.</description></item><item><title>Quick Serve it!</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/simple-http-servers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 11:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/simple-http-servers/</guid><description>Sometimes you need to serve a directory to a group in a small room.
Using Node
npm install http-server -g http-server # another port # http-server -p 9080 Want to run it forever in production? Run it forever
forever start ../node_modules/http-server/bin/http-server # path the last argument to http-server and path it to where you want Using Python
python -m SimpleHTTPServer # specify port number via python -m SimpleHTTPServer 8080 Using Php</description></item><item><title>Develop Java in Sublime</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/run-java-in-sublime/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 22:09:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/run-java-in-sublime/</guid><description>This is for mac on sublime.
It makes it a bit easier to build and run java everytime you compile. Speeds up from moving to terminal each time.
using sublime or text editor is sometimes unmanagable for java but the anti-eclipse club is strong&amp;hellip;
//Build and run java, works on OSX 10.9 Mavericks and Sublime and up { &amp;quot;cmd&amp;quot;: [&amp;quot;javac \&amp;quot;$file_name\&amp;quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; java \&amp;quot;$file_base_name\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;], &amp;quot;shell&amp;quot;: true, &amp;quot;file_regex&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;^(...*?):([0-9]*):?([0-9]*)&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;selector&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;source.java&amp;quot; }</description></item><item><title>Google Glass at MHacks</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/mhacks-spring14-/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 23:27:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/mhacks-spring14-/</guid><description>These are some notes over the night of January 17-19th for Mhacks_III in its Raw blog form. My friend Jose and I both brought our Google Glass and we were determined to build a cool Google glass Hack at MHacks this year in Detroit.
The hack: Codename Archimedies using the glass as a medical device for assisted living. Tech used. + Mirror API + Bootstrap + PHP/Yii + MySQL</description></item><item><title>Developing for Google Glass</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/developing-for-glass/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 15:25:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/developing-for-glass/</guid><description>Some caveats to a good glass app Inspired by the good principals of a good web app.
follows similar style and UX principals in other apps natural usage in day to day life. GDK on the client, voice recognition and translate avaliable on the client. Standard Android API and Paradigms
Types - invocation - elements GDK OK GLASS MIRROR MENU ITEM GDK + Mirror Timeline card Gesture Detector - touch pad movement Voice Trigger - specify use Card Scroller &amp;amp; Cards(builder)- build timeline cards and arrange to scroll through them Live Card - real time info</description></item><item><title>Glass Memory Assistant</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/glass-memory-assistant/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:37:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/glass-memory-assistant/</guid><description>I worked on a Glass memory assistant at a past Hackathon. It ended up not working out well but many companies are going into space. This was put together for an exercise that required responding to how a technology today can fill a gap in technology in the past in a more efficient way.
From a study in 2001 in leveraging personal mobile tech and using natural language recognition operation</description></item><item><title>Tricks when Developing on Android with Java</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/android-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 16:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/android-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Components of android Activities -email client Services -music player Content Providers - Note taking app or contacts Broadcast Receiver -The intent deliverer Logcat filtering without eclipse.
adb logcat | grep --line-buffered &amp;quot;mysearch&amp;quot; to pipe out to txt file
adb logcat | grep --line-buffered &amp;quot;mysearch&amp;quot; &amp;gt; mylog.txt open and visit website via intent
adb bash am start -a android.intent.action.VIEW -d http://www.stackoverflow.com Build from commandline an android project (replace &amp;lsquo;Hello with name of Project&amp;rsquo;)</description></item><item><title>Google Glass: First Impressions</title><link>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/living-with-glass/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 16:08:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanleyzhengnyc.github.io/blog/post/living-with-glass/</guid><description>Wearing glass in the wild is a very social experience. Often it draws a few stares and people are curious, is it on or is it off? What does it do.
This blog reflecting on a developer who returned glass after 30 days http://blog.rememberlenny.com/blog/2014/01/05/i-return-ed-my-google-glass-after-30-days/ struck
Impressions Voice - the gdk offered voice recognition is amazing good, and its suprising that this is performed on the client side. Also new apps sideloaded also can have their apps specified by the voicd command trigger predefined.</description></item></channel></rss>