<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>javascript on Stanley Zheng</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/tags/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in javascript on Stanley Zheng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 12:06:44 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stanzheng.com/blog/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NPM Food - Emojis &#43; NPM Packaging</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2017/npm-food-unicode-emoji/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 12:06:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2017/npm-food-unicode-emoji/</guid><description>npm install -g food If we installed this package from NPM, what do we expect this to do? What kind of interface would we expect this to implement? I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure; This was one of those ideas that I had a spark of an idea and started four years ago. Watching the package go stale and be empty for years reminded me I should try and provide another valuable node package to the world.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw 3 - Mocha</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:24:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-3/</guid><description>Here is my solution to Sharpen Your Saw 3. We had Steve Hackbarth down again to teach about a core skill in development: testing. We used the popular test runner Mocha.
The project went through different setups proving although complex, a stateless purely functional component is easy to test. Repo.
Each pull request represents a solution.
Here is my solution.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw 2 - Async</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw-2/</guid><description>About Hacking Async with Steve Hackbarth, here are a few solutions provided by our fellow meetup users Steve Hackbarth is back again this February to lead an interactive meet-up to discuss problem-solving using Javascript and other useful utilities. Be sure to bring your laptop so you can participate in the exercises.
Slides: http://ursahealth.github.io/async.html
The challenge was to find all word with the most synonyms in the phrase. &amp;ldquo;May the force be with you&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Sharpen Your Saw - Lodash</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/post/sharpen-your-saw/</guid><description>Intro &amp;ldquo;Steve Hackbarth presented Sharpen your Saw, discussing problem-solving using JavaScript and other useful&amp;rdquo; utilities. Participants were encouraged to bring laptops to participate in code exercises.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the topics covered by the Monday Norfolk.js meetup:
Steve Hackbarth presented Sharpen your Saw, discussing problem-solving using Javascript and other useful utilities. Participants were encouraged to bring laptops to participate in code exercises.
Participants could use jsfiddle.net Some of the utilities used were underscore.</description></item></channel></rss>