<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWS on Stanley Zheng</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in AWS on Stanley Zheng</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 10:01:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stanzheng.com/blog/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amazon Web Services Certified!</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/aws-solutions-certified/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/aws-solutions-certified/</guid><description>I was able to get my solutions architect Exam this past week and wanted to share my experience. This was the solutions architect exam available before Feb 2018 and not the new one.
INTRO Amazon maintains 9 different certifications and specialties that you become certified in. Most of the certifications are valid for 2 years. Some are pre-requests for others; for example, the Solutions Architect Associate is required before taking the professional but some exams such as the Cloud Practioner have no requisites.</description></item><item><title>Serverless IAM Permissions</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/serverless-iam-permissions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 10:01:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/serverless-iam-permissions/</guid><description>How do we create an IAM (Identity Access Management) user with the bare minimum permissions to access the resources it needs for Serverless? What do the individual IAM services and permissions mean?
Intro In the wonderful world of Amazon lambda, you write the function code and execute it on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure. But outside of just Amazon Lambda there are multiple other Amazon resources your Lambda taps into including API Gateway, Cloudformation and more depending on what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description></item><item><title>AWS Lambda with Python</title><link>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/simple-aws-lambda-python/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:06:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://stanzheng.com/blog/2018/simple-aws-lambda-python/</guid><description>Update The bundle of this code is interesting but the bundle is huge! I recommend trying out either of the solutions below.
Serverless Framework AWS Serverless Application Model Intro AWS Lambda is a hosted platform for running code in the Amazon ecosystem. It supports multiple runtimes including Python! I found that although writing the logic code is easy, there are some unintuitive things that I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled over.</description></item></channel></rss>